<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John Paul Brammer</title>
    <description>Bold cultural and political commentary from America&#39;s margins.</description>
    <link>http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 21:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 21:31:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>President-Elect Trump: Last Week Tonight with John Oliver</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/president-elect-trump-last-week-tonight-with-john-oliver/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/president-elect-trump-last-week-tonight-with-john-oliver/</guid>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I am Chicano, I am queer, I am the “other.” Where will I fit in Trump’s America?</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And we will survive this too. And there will be a future for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that what I wanted was an heirloom. Something physical, something expensive, something with weight and texture and worth that I could pass down to someone. What it was, I didn’t know. To whom it would go was also a mystery. But in my mind, I imagined that, simply by having it, I could guarantee that there would be a future for me, and that there would be a future for people like me, and that theirs would be a world where they didn’t lose sleep over nights like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t hard to figure out where the instinct came from. I couldn’t see myself in the America ahead. I had only prepared for “President Clinton,” spoken casually on the television or over the radio in the barbershop in a business-as-usual America. I had never stopped to picture myself in president Donald Trump’s America, not only because I didn’t expect it to ever exist, but also because I am at odds with the vision it submits — I am Chicano. I am queer. I am the “other.” Where would I fit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the election results are real, even if they feel like they shouldn’t be. On the morning after, it felt incorrect for the M train to be chugging along the track just outside my apartment, stopping, opening, ferrying. Outside, I heard a woman laugh. How? I wondered. I took these mundane activities to be collusion with the injustice at hand. Don’t people know the world has been canceled?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need something to give to someone, says a crude instinct. A me-shaped gap has opened up in the fabric of my world, and I am a non-person watching another America in some other reality where I am invisible. I want to make myself concrete. I want to have something that will outlast me when I’m gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to picture myself existing beyond today, but I only see me in the past tense, as one of the weathered, weary queers who survived. They exist here, in the now, and I see their tired faces from time to time in blue-lit nightclubs — a vague, intense battle behind them, they exist in a different world inside of ours that I don’t understand. I realize now that I haven’t learned a thing from them, that I have barely spoken to them. Because although I have also struggled, and although I have also been kicked and spat upon, and called every slur in the book, I have also considered myself to be fortunate. I am living on prime real-estate on the cosmic arc of justice, right where it crescendos and begins to bend downward into a frictionless slope. But that’s not the case anymore. Soon some other ungrateful person who isn’t me will take my place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are the future elders. I’ve never stopped to truly consider it until today. I’ve never felt saddled with the burden. Was I so naïve as to think we would be the post-queers, unencumbered by identity? Absolutely not. Maybe some of the white gays were already eyeing property there, in that white male neighborhood where they were being invited to more and more dinner parties. But not us. Not me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did, however, see myself chugging along on an engine pushing forward and forward and forward. I subconsciously thought that, as bad as things got, and whatever hiccups might occur along the way, the direction was right. We were moving, and we were moving without me, and gravity would do a good deal of the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ignorance of the activist who thought progress moved this way. Who had never seen the worst possible thing actually happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are the future elders. For the first time in my life, I feel that weight in my hands. Because what we do now, with our backs against the wall, will define us, and how we are defined will provide the context for how those who come after us will live. And I find myself caring deeply about how they will live, because they have a chance to live better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Mira, mi gente, mi familia. *To be born in this world as you have been—queer, of color, woman, immigrant—is to inherit a word in an incomplete sentence. We are required to write, and we are required to read what came before, to read and read and read until we know ourselves, and know where we are going, and what we must do to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is our inheritance in a country that gives us little. You, and me, and the “us” before, and the “us” after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;El Choque — *the Shock. I’ve been in this place enough times to give it a name, the dizzy place where I wake up and someone is crying, where something awful has happened and my mind reels as I’m brought up to speed. Here I am again on the morning after the Orlando Pulse shooting, walking to the bodega to get my roommate a bottle of water because he’s having a panic attack, that awful *ping *when I walk through the door. I think of it, the *ping,&lt;/em&gt; and it still has the transportive power to put me back there. I don’t say it out loud, because I feel it’s taboo to compare anything to Pulse. But I find myself saying a lot of the same things now as I did on the day of the massacre, the same promises to fight and to come together and to help people heal. I wonder if pain is pain is pain, showing up on different days and manifesting in different ways but hitting the same place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is what we’ll leave you, and this is what you’ll take from us — ancestral knowledge of how to survive the pain. How to sneak yourself out little by little. How to, in the margins, blossom, erupt into colors, radiate. How to bite your tongue when you have to and how to sharpen it to a fine point when you have no other option. How to mourn, as we must often do, but also, how to thrive; how to turn nothing into something, as we always have and always will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world ticks by, and I suspect this surreal feeling won’t last. The train will stop enough times, and people will laugh enough times, and this will feel normal again, and we will adapt again, and there will be a place for me here. That’s the great thing about us. We build our own homes at the end of the day. We belong everywhere where we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we will survive this too. And there will be a future for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 08:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/i-am-chicano-i-am-queer-i-am-the-other-dot-where-will-i-fit-in-trumps-america/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/i-am-chicano-i-am-queer-i-am-the-other-dot-where-will-i-fit-in-trumps-america/</guid>
        
        <category>lgbtq</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Donald Trump nightmare will endure for Latinos regardless</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Despite higher than usual early voting among Latin communities, Trump could still succeed. Even if he doesn’t, he’s made racism against us fashionable again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nightmare truly began when Donald Trump &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2015/aug/26/donald-trump-in-iowa-obama-esque-campaign-but-the-same-mouthy-mogul&quot;&gt;threw&lt;/a&gt; Jorge Ramos out of a press conference in August last year. Some might argue it was when he called Mexican immigrants “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2015/jul/02/donald-trump-racist-claims-mexico-rapes&quot;&gt;rapists&lt;/a&gt;” the month before, but the beast hadn’t yet emerged, hadn’t yet been given a clear face or features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Go back to Univision!” Trump shouted as Ramos was escorted out of the room. The familiar syntax was not lost on us Latinos, who have been told to “go back” for as long as we’ve been in the United States, whether we were born here or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before he was forcibly removed, Ramos was criticizing Trump for effectively saying he would deport 11 million undocumented people and build a 1,900-mile border wall. Well, Trump skirted those specifics, but that was the reality of what he was proposing. We Latinos were put in a familiar place – where we are merely numbers or parasites to the economy, seen not for our worth as human beings but for our worth as laborers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Al mal tiempo, buena cara, *goes an old Mexican proverb. “To the bad times, good face.” When I first delved into the world of activism, I used to hold the saying in contempt. It seemed to feed into the bottomless humility of the Mexican American in the face of oppression, the immigrant family, the Chicano who doesn’t want to make a fuss. It painted us, I thought, as a people who merely stood by while bad things happened to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching the Trump campaign, being its first scapegoats, I felt we were in that helpless place where our only option was to endure. The slogan Make America Great Again encapsulated exactly how we are seen in this country. We are the unclean other, our culture dilutes the purity of America’s white citizens who must be protected from us. Make America great again – by kicking us out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Violence &lt;a href=&quot;http://americasvoice.org/trumphatemap/&quot;&gt;against Latinos surged&lt;/a&gt;, at Trump rallies and across the country. Xenophobia and racism were whipped into a fever pitch by the demagogue’s rants, his constant attacks on our families and our neighbors. “Send them back” was a phrase I heard more in those months than I ever had in my life. “You have to go back” became a common response to everything I wrote. Something had changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was Trump’s attack on US district court judge Gonzalo P Curiel, born in Indiana and of Mexican descent, that saw our worst fears begin to take shape in reality. Trump, then the presumptive Republican nominee, accused Curiel, who was overseeing a class action lawsuit against Trump University, of being biased simply because of his Mexican heritage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember watching the debacle unfold and thinking: “So this is how he’ll silence us as president.” All of us. For Trump, it has never been about immigration. It’s been about stoking racism against brown people, against black people, against the “other”. “He’s a member of a club or society very strongly pro-Mexican,” Trump said of Curiel. “Which is all fine. But I say he’s got bias.” It harkened back to McCarthyism. This is what he meant when he said he would make America great again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things took a dip into the absurd with the infamous Cinco de Mayo &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/realdonaldtrump/status/728297587418247168?lang=en&quot;&gt;taco bowl tweet.&lt;/a&gt; Trump, smiling and without irony, as if he hadn’t advocated for the mass deportation of our people and hadn’t called us criminals and thugs, tweeted: “I love Hispanics!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was beyond parody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, many hope that the long nightmare is about to draw to a close. But Trump could still pull off a win. And even if he doesn’t, the Trump machine will roll on, with or without him. We have on our hands a significant population of angry white citizens who blame us for all their frustrations. Things are about to get worse for us, not better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It happens in cycles. America’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/codeswitch/2015/09/08/437579834/mass-deportation-may-sound-unlikely-but-its-happened-before&quot;&gt;last mass deportation&lt;/a&gt; of Latinos and Mexican Americans happened during the Great Depression. Approximately 2 million Mexicans and Mexican-Americans were rounded up and ejected from the country. And leading up to Trump, xenophobia in the Republican party was already the norm. Trump merely brought the subtext to the fore, bolded it and added several exclamation points. It’s a recipe for disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Al mal tiempo, buena cara. *I used to hate the phrase, but now I think of it daily. It helps me survive the daily inanities of the election cycle, the daily ways we are dehumanized. It’s not putting on a smile and pretending the bad times aren’t happening. It is a radical act of survival. It is a resolute affirmation in the face of adversity: I will make it through this. I will live to see the better days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 08:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/the-donald-trump-nightmare-will-endure-for-latinos-regardless/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/the-donald-trump-nightmare-will-endure-for-latinos-regardless/</guid>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        <category>race</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>7 Things I Wish I Knew Before Coming Out as Gay</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming out was the best thing I’ve ever done for myself. I can’t think of any other life decision I’ve made that has impacted my self-esteem and my quality of life so positively. That being said, coming out came with its fair share of struggles that I felt I had to navigate alone. To all the gay men who have just come out or are in the process of coming out, I hope this list helps make your experience a little easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Acceptance starts with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Acceptance” is a word that takes on a whole new meaning when you come out. You will discover that there will be people, even people you care about, who will never accept you for being gay. On top of that, you may not even find acceptance in the gay community. You may find yourself trying to be more masculine or more feminine just to fit in. But while acceptance from others can feel really good, remember that you can’t be so afraid of losing people that you lose yourself. There will always be people who aren’t pleased with the way you are, and that can hurt. A lot. But when you accept yourself, you empower yourself, and no one’s opinion can take that from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. You’re going to feel a lot of pressure to look a certain way.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels good to be looked at, especially now that you can look back. But you will quickly realize that the gay community seems to be populated with Calvin Klein models, and you might look at yourself and feel like you don’t measure up. There will be body types and molds that you will be told to strive for, and there will be pressure everywhere to conform. Trust me, gay media doesn’t help. But you need to remember that you’re fine just the way you are, and you should apply that positive attitude to the gay people around you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. You’re going to want to protect your platonic gay friendships.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All your friends are great and you should cherish them equally. But there will come a time when a boy breaks your heart or someone calls you a slur, and you will need someone who really understands. Platonic gay friends are like unicorns and you should protect them as such. Oh, and definitely don’t let some boy come between you. It’s never worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. You’re going to want to pick your battles.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You just came out, and suddenly the world seems more bigoted than ever. The fact is it’s always been this way. You’re just awake to it now. As an out gay person, you have the opportunity to speak out and use your voice to better the world. But it’s important to remember that you can’t fight every battle, and it’s incredibly taxing on your mental health to always be angry. Conserve your energy and use it when it’s really needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. You were once closeted too. Don’t pressure people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, it’s annoying when that guy you want to date just can’t seem to accept the fact that he’s gay and come out. But he doesn’t owe that to you or anybody else. People come out when they’re good and ready, just like you did. Cut them some slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Look out for your whole community.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the G forgets the L and the B and the T. But try to remember, we gay men owe a great deal to lesbian, bisexual, and trans activists both past and present. Community is important, LGBT history is important, and while you may never understand the unique struggles of others you can still support them just as they’ve supported you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Don’t be ashamed that you didn’t do it sooner.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you meet that 18-year-old who has been out of the closet for two years, you’re going to be jealous. Why couldn’t you come out sooner? Why did you waste so much time? But remember, everyone is on a different path in life. The most important thing is that you take this time, right here, right now, to be the best, fullest &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; you can be. Who knows? Maybe some young person will see that and decide: Today is the day I come out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 07:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/7-things-i-wish-i-knew-before-coming-out-as-gay/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/7-things-i-wish-i-knew-before-coming-out-as-gay/</guid>
        
        <category>lgbtq</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Won’t Let Donald Trump Use Queer Latinx Bodies To Fuel Islamophobia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;He has threatened to take our families. He has threatened to take our civil rights. Now, Donald Trump is reminding us that not even our grief will be spared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wake of Sunday’s massacre, where 49 of our LGBTQ brothers and sisters were taken from us, most of whom were Latinx, Trump thought first not of the slain, but of himself. He congratulated himself in a tweet for “being right on radical Islamic terrorism.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Appreciate the congrats for being right on radical Islamic terrorism, I don’t want congrats, I want toughness &amp;amp; vigilance. We must be smart!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;— Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/742034549232766976&quot;&gt;June 12, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a better world, this breathtaking paucity of sympathy would immediately bring a candidate’s presidential ambitions to a halt. But not Trump, whose campaign was founded on fear and whose singular talent appears to be inciting enough outrage to keep his face plastered across media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did not even have time to process the magnitude of the massacre before Trump, seeing an opportunity to drum up the hatred his campaign depends so dearly on, pounced on it. He congratulated himself again, this time for calling for a ban on Muslims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What has happened in Orlando is just the beginning. Our leadership is weak and ineffective. I called it and asked for the ban. Must be tough&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;— Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/742096033207844864&quot;&gt;June 12, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trump is either overlooking the fact that Omar Mateen was born in New York or this is his way of proposing that even American-born Muslims will be “banned.” This is where we are at. The candidate of a major political party might be announcing major, life-shattering policies through sloppily composed tweets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought Trump could sink no lower. But that’s never a safe assumption with Trump. Today, he thanked the LGBT community (again on his Twitter account) and said that Hillary would bring in more people that will threaten our freedoms and beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you to the LGBT community! I will fight for you while Hillary brings in more people that will threaten your freedoms and beliefs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;— Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/742771576039460864&quot;&gt;June 14, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will ignore that Trump has said he would look into installing Supreme Court justices who would overturn same-sex marriage. This is a practice I have become accustomed to: Ignoring all the other ridiculous things Trump has said in order to focus in on one, specific ridiculous thing Trump has said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, I want to focus on the fact that he thanked the LGBT community. So let me be clear, Mr. Trump: We are not in solidarity with you, nor do we want your thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bodies of our slain LGBTQ Latinx brothers and sisters weren’t even counted when you tweeted yourself a pat on the back. How dare you use them as political props. How dare you stand in our grief. How dare you, knowing damn well how we Latinxs feel about you, erase and whitewash the identities of the massacred to promote your agenda of hatred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where were you in condemning radical rightwing Christianity in the wake of the Planned Parenthood attacks? Not to be found, of course, because you wouldn’t dare do anything to turn Evangelicals off of you. Even though you could barely list a Bible verse that you’ve read. Even though you are the antithesis of everything Christianity is meant to represent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be able to fool white nationalists. You might be able to fool a menagerie of America’s racists and xenophobes and misogynists. But the rest of us see right through you, Mr. Trump. You are no ally of ours. You’re a cheap, dishonest salesperson looking for the next opportunity to peddle your wares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not fear Islam, Mr. Trump. The Muslims in my life, many of whom are LGBT, are some of the most inspiring, kindhearted, beautiful people I’ve ever met. No. I fear fundamentalism. Whether it take Islam or Christianity by name, I fear it because it seeks to snuff out precious life and dehumanize anyone who dares to speak up against it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means you, Mr. Trump. The fundamentalism you are inspiring is ripping this nation apart, and as evidenced by your strong hatred of the press, you are trying to silence any who would challenge you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it won’t work. If anything, this is only drawing our communities closer together. If there were an ounce of humanity rattling around in your surely hollow soul, I’d ask you to look at the solidarity Muslims are offering to the victims of the shooting in Orlando. I have more in common with them than I ever will with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, Mr. Trump, your scare tactics won’t work on us. We’ve already seen you what you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, happy birthday, you heinous tangerine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 19:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/we-wont-let-donald-trump-use-queer-latinx-bodies-to-fuel-islamophobia/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/we-wont-let-donald-trump-use-queer-latinx-bodies-to-fuel-islamophobia/</guid>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I’ve Decided To Start Dressing More Femininely</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All my life, I worried that wearing flamboyant clothes would mean putting a target on my back. But in the wake of the shooting at Pulse, I realized that I’ve been sacrificing a huge part of myself for a safety that was never guaranteed in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There comes a time in&lt;/strong&gt; every young queer’s life when they are struck by lightning.\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, that time comes on a brisk spring morning in rural Oklahoma, when I’m standing behind the middle school, waiting for the bell to ring for first period. Two people are standing with me: Matt and Patrick, both of whom I consider friends. But it’s complicated. They’ve been acting differently around me lately. Sometimes they suddenly stop talking when I walk up to them. They smirk. They know something I don’t. It makes me nervous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m wearing a green John Deere tractor shirt and jeans that are one size too big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey,” Matt says to Patrick. He nods in my direction. “Talk to him about shirts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An electric pulse shoots down my body. This is it. I’ve been caught. All I can do now is play dumb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shirts?” I say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patrick looks at me. He points. His posturing seems rehearsed, like this is something he’s been planning to do. Something he’s been practicing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s my fucking shirt,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s true. It is his shirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The person I’d like to be doesn’t wear John Deere tractor shirts. Instead, he is dressed like the beautiful people in my mother’s fashion magazines, which I keep secretly stashed under my bed. He wears elegant jewelry, blouses in exciting patterns and vibrant colors, fabric that flows and moves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every night I watch &lt;em&gt;The Look for Less&lt;/em&gt; (hosted by a pre-Fox News Elisabeth Hasselbeck) on the Style Network with my sister. We like to tear apart the bargain outfits they come up with, because they always fall short of the designer original. I am perhaps the only boy in our little patch of countryside who daydreams about Tyra Banks finding him and recruiting him to be on &lt;em&gt;America’s Next Top Model&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Patrick is a normal boy, and I want to be a normal boy too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m wearing a John Deere tractor shirt because I’m hiding. I’m wearing it because I saw Patrick wearing it, and Patrick is a normal boy, and I want to be a normal boy too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patrick sees it differently. He tells me I’m obsessed with him. He tells me he’s been catching me looking at him. He tells me I’m in love with him. “You’re a faggot,” he says, and there it is. Lightning. Baptism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next few months of my life are &lt;em&gt;faggot&lt;/em&gt; this and &lt;em&gt;faggot&lt;/em&gt; that. There are days when I hear it more than I hear my name. Lunchtime, Patrick slaps a hot dog in my face. “You like that, faggot?” He says. “Faggots are supposed to like that.” A soccer game, he kicks a ball at me and it hits me in the groin, &lt;em&gt;smack, sting,&lt;/em&gt; I double over. He tells me I don’t have a dick. He tells me to stop pretending to be hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After queer people are struck by lightning for the first time, we are acutely aware of the space around us — of the dark cloud hovering just above our heads. It could strike at any moment. If you look a certain way, if you act a certain way, if you dress a certain way, the odds of being struck go up. Queerness is a breach of contract, one that often carries with it the penalty of violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Talk to me about shirts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eleven years later,&lt;/strong&gt; I sit at This n’ That, a divey gay bar in Brooklyn, with my friend Levi, who does drag on the side. It’s a cute bar, shaped like a TNT barrel on the inside, but it feels cramped tonight. Levi asks if I want to step outside with him while he smokes. It’s early May but it’s chilly and rainy. People wait in line in their coats, then check them at the door to reveal their club attire, their fishnets and their high-waisted shorts and their crop tops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve just moved to New York, and like anyone who has ever been tossed into the too-much-ness of this city, I’m wrestling with the feeling that I’m not standing out enough. That feeling intensifies when I’m next to Levi, or, as she’s known tonight, Miss Thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miss Thing is in her full drag attire — hair high to God, a strappy bondage-esque gown with sheer and leather elements, nails so long I wonder how she holds a drink, face beat to perfection. I ask her if she has trouble getting to the bar dressed like that. She laughs. “I usually change at the place,” she says. “But when someone whistles at me I like to slap my ass and wink.” I feel the eyes on her from people walking by. Glances. They make me nervous. She doesn’t seem to care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My style at this point can best be described as “white dad on vacation”: floral patterns, my only conceit to femininity, on button-up shirts. Short shorts, a compromise between a strong desire to show skin and a stronger desire to stay in my comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My style at this point can best be described as “white dad on vacation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s not the real me. The real me is still very much into fashion and very bored with collared button-ups in every color, pattern, and print. I don’t know who made the decision that men’s clothing had to be so limited, but all the good stuff is in the women’s section. That’s where the interesting jewelry is. That’s where clothes do more than just hang off you. They wrap, they flow, they move. They transform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tell Miss Thing that I want to start exploring some new looks. Here, in New York, outfits are put together to dazzle and impress. It excites me because these are looks that feel tied to something older, to a queer history I’d never embraced. Here was a place where, maybe, I could finally be myself, a place where I could wear the things I want to wear — because here, someone else was already wearing it, only better and on roller skates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also tell Miss Thing that I’m afraid. Without going into much detail, I tell her that I’ve survived violence in the past. “Well,” she says, “this will be like therapy!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, we blink through our hangovers and go shopping in Manhattan. Our first stop is Topshop. Levi, in his boy attire, starts picking things out, things that are already making me nervous. “This is cute,” he says, holding something up that tells me he thinks I’m ready to make the leap from “Are you masc, bro?” to “Season 9 of &lt;em&gt;RuPaul’s Drag Race&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Could we start with something a little…less?” I ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He cackles. “You poor thing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He throws me a bone: a black sheer shirt he tells me will show off my chest. I walk into the dressing room. I try it on. I love it. It’s not the me I’d dreamt of in rural Oklahoma — the me I could have been if I had been allowed to grow up uninterrupted — but it’s a baby step in the right direction. The seed of doubt is definitely there, and I worry that it will bloom into full-blown anxiety by the time I get home. But today is about breaking barriers. So I buy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take it home in a bag. I put the bag in my closet. It sits there for a month before I return it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Passing” — the ability&lt;/strong&gt; to blend in with the straight world — is not a privilege all of us queer people have. But a lot of gay men do, including myself. It isn’t fun to hide. But it will protect you from lightning.\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, I don’t really present as myself. I mean that in a way that goes beyond my clothing. Presentation is the way I talk, the way I walk, the way I act, the things I admit to liking, the people I surround myself with, the way I won’t hold hands with a guy in public. I present as a negotiation between myself and the space around me, a compromise between vibrancy and violence. It’s a compromise queer people around the world make every day. Flamboyancy means drawing attention to yourself. Being openly queer draws attention to yourself. Attention means they see you, and when they see you, they can hurt you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stick to my boring floral button-ups and short shorts and masculine mannerisms because that’s where I feel safe: in the privileged bubble of the gay male mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We, those of us in the mainstream, seem to have departed from our radical roots years ago, a shift that was finalized after the legalization of same-sex marriage in 2015. Being gay never felt more normal, more tolerated, more boring, more safe. I tell myself I will work on being the queer I want to be later, when I feel bold enough to leave the bubble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, Pulse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m in New York when&lt;/strong&gt; the news breaks. Being a gay Latino working in media today means full immersion. I can’t look away. I can’t stop reading. My knee-jerk reaction is to take a bus to D.C., the city I lived in before New York, to see my friends. I feel I have to see for myself that they’re alive and OK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a candlelight vigil in Dupont Circle, my friend Blake and I head to Trade, a local gay bar, for a drink. In the immediate days following the tragedy, the gay bar takes on the sacred significance of a temple. We go without thinking, because that’s where we’re supposed to be. We take turns letting it out — the hurt and the fear and the anger — because that’s what we need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s dark outside, and the bar is nearly empty. The club lights are on and the music is playing, but for no one in particular. I don’t know if it’s empty because it’s a Tuesday night or because people are afraid to be here. (I’m afraid to be here.) We sit in the window and sip our drinks, watching people on the sidewalk stroll past. “Don’t they know,” he said, “how much we’ve been holding back?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I consider all the ways I have muted myself. All that, and I can still be killed just for standing in a gay bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cry a lot in the days that follow. Most of the victims are Latino boys, my community, and that hits me hard. But there is another pain, a reckoning, and I think a lot of gay men and other queer people are in that place with me. I consider all the ways I have muted myself. All the ways I have hidden. All the ways I have held back and apologized and changed. All that, and I can still be killed just for standing in a gay bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our senses heightened after Orlando, allowing us to see the world as it had always been — and we saw that it was unfair, had always been unfair, even though some of us had become complacent. Why were there gay bars in the first place? Why were people killing us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t they know how much we’ve been holding back?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize now, in the wake of Orlando, that I have been sacrificing something special for a safety that was never guaranteed in the first place — a safety that asked so much of me and gave so little in return, but a safety I had become comfortable with nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was used to the spitting and the kicking and the shouting — but this, what I was suppressing in myself, was a different kind of violence. I could leave &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; at the door, leave &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; at home, stuff &lt;em&gt;those&lt;/em&gt; in a closet somewhere, and I would be safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orlando changed all of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I realize, now,&lt;/strong&gt; everything I have lost. I realize that if a homophobe were to kill me tomorrow, I’d die a repressed, second-rate version of the person I could have been. That’s scary. Scarier than the alternative, even, because if I’ve learned one thing, it’s that you can do your best to hide — but they’ll still find you, even if you’re doing your best to walk, talk, dress, and act like everything you’re not. I don’t want to be something I’m not anymore. Even if that something is “safer.” There will always be the threat of lightning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If a homophobe were to kill me tomorrow, I’d die a repressed, second-rate version of the person I could have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s privilege there. There are queer people here and around the world who can’t openly present as themselves without being killed. These are so many oppressive norms we have to dismantle. And while the word “dismantle” sounds like taking a sledgehammer to a building, today it looks more like skipping down the street with my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four of us are drunk, stumbling out of a nightclub in our head-to-toe looks, glitter and eyeshadow and gold. I never went back for that shirt I returned, but what I’m wearing tonight makes up for it, a flowy black number. “You’re giving me dumpster sorceress,” one of my friends says. I look a mess, to be honest. But that’s OK. New York is never bigger than it is on nights like these, when the streets are empty but the lights are on. There’s plenty of time. There’s plenty of space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Faggot!” someone yells as we fly by, and I’m not sure which one of us he’s talking to. But I choose to laugh, and suddenly I feel bigger than the word as it recedes into the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t necessarily feel safe, but I do feel free.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 19:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/why-ive-decided-to-start-dressing-more-femininely/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/why-ive-decided-to-start-dressing-more-femininely/</guid>
        
        <category>lgbtq</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why It Matters That It Was Latin Night at Pulse</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Pulse was a space for celebration, especially on Latin night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t look at their faces. When I can look at them without crying, without feeling a sharp twinge in my gut, I think that’s how I’ll know that I’m OK again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up on Sunday to the sound of my roommate crying. The world was still coming into focus when I walked outside to get him a bottle of cold water from the deli across the street. He said he couldn’t feel his face. He was having an anxiety attack. I was in a stupor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ping! Tragedy has a way of making everything more present, more detailed. The bell rang as I walked through the door into the deli, and the sound was so distinct and shrill that I immediately knew this was a sound I would always remember whenever I thought back to this day, and I knew I would think back to this day. I was that lucid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My roommate is a bisexual Latino. I am a gay Latino. We had been out at a gay club just the night before. When I returned with his water, we hugged. I remember feeling like it was all of me that was being hugged, because we had a mutual understanding of this tragedy. It was Latin night at Pulse nightclub in Orlando: “That could have been us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that day, without warning, in come the faces. In come the names. I have an odd switch that flips when truly awful things happen, and I am able to keep my cool. I become a caretaker. I flutter around like a hummingbird from flower to flower making sure everyone is OK. But it’s at night, when I see the faces of the victims that I break down. I lose it. I bawl into my pillow. I bite it, hit it, throw it. I can’t look at all those dead Latino boys. I just can’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel the pain of my LGBTQ brothers and sisters. In this time of great need, the solidarity of my community is what keeps me going. I get a text from someone I haven’t heard from in a while saying they’re thinking of me and asking if I’m OK. I get a Facebook message: “Hey. I appreciate you.” I get a hug, and we hug a little longer than we usually do. It’s a poignant togetherness, one that feels stronger, more powerful even than the one I felt the day same-sex marriagebecame the law of the land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is another pain, a specific pain, that is proving harder to process. This pain has a voice, a face, and a name. He says “Hola cariño” as I step into the room. He kisses me on both cheeks. His name is Victor, his name is Manuel, his name is Luis and Jesús and Chuy, and maybe he is me, too, and in my head, he was gunned down. That’s the pain. That’s the sadness. That’s the thing that has ruined my peace of mind, the reason I couldn’t sleep last night. Us. They killed us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They killed us while we were holding our drinks and dancing bachata. They killed us while we were smiling, while we were slapping each other on the asses and calling each other “perra” and “guapa.” They killed us where we meet each other, where we ask where our families are from, and where we crack playful jokes about Mexico or Puerto Rico or Venezuela. They killed us in our sanctuary, where we are at our most free. Not just free to be queer. Not just free to be Latino. But free to be both at the same time. That’s where they killed us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say “they,” and I do not say “the shooter,” because the grim reality is they have always been around and they have always killed us. Entire political careers can be founded on the platform of ripping us from our homes and away from our families. They lock up our transgender sisters in Immigration and Customs Enforcement where they are harassed and assaulted and raped, women who were fleeing violence only to meet more of it. Today, they want to build a wall. We don’t even want to think about what they might do tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has never been a place safe enough, holy enough where they won’t kill us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The LGBTQ identities of the victims of Sunday’s massacre must not be erased. Nor should the fact that most of the victims were Latinos. It takes nothing away from unity to acknowledge this. In fact, it creates solidarity. Every single victim from this tragedy matters. For some of us, though, the psychic trauma is more acute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will never forget their faces. Not only because I feel it is my moral imperative to carry them, but also because they are etched into my mind. They are people I already know, because I know how they move, how they talk, how they smile, how they hug me and touch me and are me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we move forward from this tragedy, we bring their spirits with us. We will leave no part of them behind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 19:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/why-it-matters-that-it-was-latin-night-at-pulse/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/why-it-matters-that-it-was-latin-night-at-pulse/</guid>
        
        <category>race</category>
        
        <category>lgbtq</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I already had body dysmorphic disorder. Then my skin started changing color.</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One percent of Americans have vitiligo, the skin disorder made famous by Michael Jackson. I’m one of them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the third day of being locked in my apartment, it dawned on me that I would eventually have to step outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d finished off a box of cornflakes the day before. I was officially out of food, and I felt a gnawing pain at the bottom of my gut. This was hunger, the real kind, and I was left with little choice but to throw on a hoodie and head to the grocery store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I layered on as many clothes as I could, careful to avoid any mirrors. I shook as I got myself dressed, not from hunger or because I hadn’t slept the night before, but because I was afraid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was going outside. People were going to see me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My condition has a name: body dysmorphic disorder. It means obsessive preoccupation with a perceived defect in physical appearance. But I wouldn’t learn that until later. When I locked myself in my apartment for three consecutive days, it had no name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t, at that time, even a disorder. It was a series of concerns. It was squashing my ears against the sides of my head because I thought they stuck out and taking pictures of myself in profile to see how big my nose was. It was burning a dirt track around my parents’ house because I had to run until I wasn’t fat anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iocdf.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/BDD-Fact-Sheet.pdf&quot;&gt;Research on the subject&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is scarce, but BDD is a condition that some experts believe could affect at least one in every 200 people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are seven things that might help you understand it a little better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;body-dysmorphic-disorder-is-an-obsession-with-a-flaw-that-may-not-even-exist&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Body dysmorphic disorder is an obsession with a flaw that may not even exist.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did I lock myself in my apartment? Because I thought my head was too big for my body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not as in, “I can’t find a hat that fits, ha ha.” As in, I believed I looked like a bobblehead toy; that my head was so huge that people would laugh if they saw me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in the back of my mind, I knew the facts of the situation. No one had ever made fun of me for having an oversize head. Even if the size of my head were an open secret, nobody had ever treated me differently because of it. But these facts didn’t matter: The moment I persuaded myself that I had a cartoon head, I became obsessed with it. It was the only fact that mattered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a person with BDD, each perceived defect becomes the new center of the world. Everything in life is reduced to an opportunity to either confirm or deny his worst fears. For me, this looked like asking my friends, as casually I could muster, “So, do you think I have a big head?” A question that almost always elicited a, “What?” or an, “Excuse me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t help myself. I was obsessed. I was consumed. I knew how ridiculous I sounded, but the state of mind I was in compelled me to keep asking, even though I knew there was nothing anyone could say that would make me feel better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I knew that only I could see this flaw. But that didn’t make it any less real to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-use-rituals-to-cope-with-overwhelming-anxiety&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) We use rituals to cope with overwhelming anxiety&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from BDD, I suffer from generalized anxiety disorder, but even with that baseline, BDD produces anxiety more painful than any other I’ve experienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my GAD leads to a panic attack, I can usually wait it out. If I can make it an hour, the feeling will pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the panic my BDD provokes can last for days. Sometimes it lasts for weeks. The anxiety feels more urgent than the general kind, more primal. The only thing that matters is that I fix this flaw. Until it’s fixed, I can’t go on living, no matter the costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My friends and family just didn’t want to hurt my feelings, my anxiety told me, so they couldn’t be trusted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some BDD sufferers go as far as radical plastic surgery to assuage this panic. More common, however, is attempting to cover up the flaw and live normally with it hidden. For me, this involved wearing chunky sweaters, oversize hoodies — anything that bulked up my body to a size I thought was more appropriate to my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “covering” let me function, but barely. I felt like I was walking on knife’s edge. One slip-up, one stray glance into the wrong mirror, one plausibly negative comment, no matter how casual, would be enough to destroy the fragile peace of mind my clothing gave me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I didn’t have to be out in public, I’d spend my time at home taking pictures. An embarrassing number of pictures. So many pictures that whenever I’d come down from an especially intense bout of anxiety, it would take me an hour to go through my phone and delete them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behaviors like these are what people with BDD call “rituals.” They exist out of necessity. The mind looks for ways to rid itself of the stress, for something it can tangibly do to get to a better place. Anyone who suffers from obsessive-compulsive disorder will likely recognize this need for rituals. BDD acts in much the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without these rituals, there would be nothing to distract the mind from the pain of the persisting defect. In addition to spending several hours every day taking pictures, I also spent a considerable amount of time on my computer looking up ways to conceal my flaw. At the same time, I looked to confirm it: I sought out strangers online, people I thought would give me a frank answer. My friends and family just didn’t want to hurt my feelings, my anxiety told me, so they couldn’t be trusted. Internet strangers would tell me how big my head was, and then, somehow, I could fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bdd-goes-hand-in-hand-with-eating-disorders&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) BDD goes hand in hand with eating disorders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was overweight as a kid. I was biracial, too, and the combination left me with a body type that proved easy fodder for my middle school classmates. My ass was large, my chest was huge, my waist was small next to both of them, and so they would tease me for having the “body of a girl.” I learned to be ashamed of being seen, of taking up space, of looking the way I looked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mind made sense of this treatment by making it rational, even deserved: You are being bullied because you look hideous. If you looked different, people would be nicer to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was 16 the first time I purged. I would run several miles a day, so often that I burned a dirt track around my parents’ house with my feet. I starved myself. I got so thin that people were concerned. They asked if I was sick. They asked my mother if I was eating. They asked me if I was “manorexic.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took it all as a compliment. I would rather be sickly thin than fat. Even when it became painful to sit down because I had nothing between my skin and my bones, I was happy because I wasn’t heavy anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But self-loathing is fickle, and one day it flipped the script. I realized that I didn’t want to be skinny, because skinny wasn’t “manly.” I wanted to be muscular. I wanted to be bigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I could only see my body as fat: Even at my thinnest I wanted to be thinner. Then, suddenly, it was sickly. Disgusting. I was so thin that my head looked huge on my body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new defect was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pictures-and-videos-are-everywhere-now--and-that-makes-it-so-much-worse&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Pictures and videos are everywhere now — and that makes it so much worse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t imagine that BDD has ever been easy, but I think it’s made harder by a world where Snapchat and selfies pervade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like everyone wants to take a picture these days. Everyone wants to remember every moment in film. But film and photographs, like mirrors, are the enemies of anyone with BDD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It tends to go one of two ways: Either you completely avoid your own image, or you’re obsessed with it. You avoid the mirror, or you never stop looking in it. You take no pictures, or you take a thousand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If forced to confront their reflection, people with BDD are likely to spend enormous amounts of time looking at it, searching for the flaw they know is there, trying to determine if it’s real or imagined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The endless scrutiny offers no clarity. For all the time I’ve spent looking at myself, I do not know what I look like. Every mirror, every photo, every video presents a different version of me. Sometimes my flaw is proven real. Sometimes it is there but not as bad as I believed it to be. Yet even this validation doesn’t help; it only sends me seeking out more mirrors and more photos in order to confirm my relief, and this only brings me back to finding my flaw again — bad as ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite, or perhaps due to, the obsession, I hate being photographed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, please, I don’t like photos,” I say when one of my friends takes out their phone for a picture. “Please.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they take a picture anyway, I become incredibly hostile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I said I don’t like pictures. What about that do you not understand? I said &lt;em&gt;no.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am desperately trying to avoid a confrontation with my appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time I saw a video of myself, it was for work. I have a job in media, and I was asked to speak about an issue in front of a camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to push through. I didn’t want to be a bad employee. But in the end, when I had to watch and hear myself, it shattered me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked to the bathroom and stayed there for an hour. I cried. I spent time looking in the mirror, trying to rebuild an image of myself I could live with, looking for the flaws I hated so much. It wasn’t anyone’s fault. It’s living with BDD — I couldn’t stand to look at myself, but I needed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bdd-is-underresearched-and-underdiagnosed&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) BDD is underresearched and underdiagnosed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BDD can have drastic consequences beyond the day-to-day pain of the condition. Some consider suicide. In the depths of one of my episodes, I told myself I couldn’t live like this the rest of my life, that if I had to feel this way, even occasionally, it wasn’t worth going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But despite these risks, studies of BDD remain scarce, and information is difficult to find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite how common it’s now believed to be, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1414653/&quot;&gt;it often goes undiagnosed and underrecognized.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we do know is that most people with BDD suffer from other mental disorders simultaneously, the most common of which are depression and anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When an official diagnosis made me more aware of my illness, I tried to seek out a community. But this proved difficult: The very nature of the disease makes people uncomfortable with being forthcoming. They worry it might draw attention to their perceived flaw. Doing so right now, even in a relatively lucid state of mind, is a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The disease is also difficult to diagnose in men, who are far less likely to admit that they have an eating disorder or that they struggle with their appearances. That was a fear I had. According to all the societal messages I’d received, men weren’t supposed to have mental illnesses, and they certainly weren’t supposed to be worried about the way they look. At the height of my suffering, when I locked myself in my apartment for three days, I was still in the closet. I was terrified of being associated with anything people might see as feminine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But despite the “unmanliness” of worrying about one’s appearance, men still receive daily messages about what the ideal man is supposed to look like: tall, a head full of hair, muscular, and rugged. The result is a perfect storm. Men suffer from BDD, but don’t want to talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s how it was for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The limited research we do have, however, shows that men and women are about equally likely to have the disease. If we want more people to seek treatment, we must push for more research and examine how our society induces the terror of physical imperfection, then discourages its victims from seeking help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;therapy-and-medication-offer-hope-but-not-a-cure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6) Therapy and medication offer hope, but not a cure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve painted a pretty grim portrait of BDD. But I must stress that there is hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serotonin reuptake inhibitors have been shown to be effective in treating BDD. I take Zoloft and a mood stabilizer. More research is required before we know the best drugs for this particular illness, but &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2705931/&quot;&gt;studies show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that symptoms do improve after patients go on medication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s okay that I’m feeling this right now, but I know I don’t have to feel this way&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therapy is also important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the most effective form of therapy has been dialectical behavior therapy (DBT), a form of cognitive behavioral psychotherapy that focuses on mindfulness, distress tolerance, and emotional regulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DBT has taught me how better to regulate the intense emotions that my dysmorphia can provoke. It has also taught me how I can acknowledge the pain I feel and the visceral reaction my body has to my BDD while also acknowledging the facts: I am having this reaction because of my illness. It’s okay that I’m feeling this right now, but I know I don’t have to feel this way. I know that it will pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mindfulness, the practice of being present in the moment, has also proved to be very useful in my fight with BDD. Exercises vary, but one I find helpful is picking out an object and listing facts about it. This table is made of wood. This table is brown. This table has four legs. This helps me anchor myself more firmly in reality and keeps me from straying too far into obsessive, abstract fears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Treatment hasn’t cured me. But it has helped me achieve a sort of agnosticism about my appearance. I have a body. My body is just fine. My body isn’t the most important part of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-are-good-ways-to-be-there-for-someone-with-bdd--and-bad-ways&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7) There are good ways to be there for someone with BDD — and bad ways&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t tell someone with BDD that her flaw doesn’t exist. We know. If we don’t, it’s because that flaw has become the most basic fact of our universe. Neither case is helped much by debate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But being there for a friend or loved one with the disorder isn’t impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you how many phone calls I’ve had with my mother while I was going through an episode. She didn’t tell me that my flaw wasn’t there — that wouldn’t have helped — but she did remind me that my pain stemmed from a mental illness. She helped me take my mind off the flaw and redirect my focus onto the facts of my situation. And that’s perhaps the best thing you can do for people with BDD: help take their mind off it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time I had an episode, a friend asked if I wanted to take a walk. We went outside, away from my bathroom mirrors and to a place where I couldn’t take any photos, and we talked for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can also be vital to take people with BDD away from their triggers, to ask them what might set them off and help them avoid it. If they don’t want their picture taken, if they don’t want one of their physical features discussed, if being in a certain kind of environment makes them uneasy, those requests should be respected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communicating and respecting these requests might seem small to a person without BDD, but they could save a person with BDD from several hours of anxiety, pain, and wasted time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a friend or loved one feels like she might have BDD, encourage her to seek help. As with any mental illness, self-diagnosis is not suggested. Once BDD is diagnosed, that person can move forward in seeking ways to treat it, and I speak from personal experience when I say that a little bit of treatment can go a long way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a poorly understood disease. It is discussed so rarely that it is often mistaken for something else entirely: vanity, or OCD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we can all do right now is help start a dialogue about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I locked myself in my apartment for three days, nothing was more terrifying than the prospect of stepping outside where people could see me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I am healthy enough to write about my illness, to discuss my perceived flaw where everyone can read it, and to do so without sacrificing my peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progress is possible. Like most things, the first step is the hardest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 18:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/i-already-had-body-dysmorphic-disorder-then-my-skin-started-changing-color/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/i-already-had-body-dysmorphic-disorder-then-my-skin-started-changing-color/</guid>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Backing for the wall spells the end of Republican decency</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To say that the GOP has been hijacked by Donald Trump would be too generous. The party’s establishment is now fully complicit in his bigotry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump’s massive, “very serious” wall, which continues to change in projected height depending on who Trump is talking to and how he is feeling about Mexico on any given day, has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2016/jul/18/mexico-border-wall-trump-republican-platform&quot;&gt;made it&lt;/a&gt; into the official Republican party platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The border wall must cover the entirety of the southern border and must be sufficient to stop both vehicular and pedestrian traffic,” the document reads. The platform was ratified on the floor of the Republican national convention in Cleveland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, the Republican party, ostensibly a “very serious” organization, has given its formal blessing to the xenophobic pipe dream that has been the centerpiece of Trump’s campaign from the start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say “pipe dream” because the staggering amount of resources and labor it would require to build such a wall plants the project firmly in the realm of the implausible, if not the impossible. The Republican party probably knows this, and apparently the Republican party doesn’t care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, for Trump, it’s never been about whether or not he can actually fulfill the promises he makes. He only cares about being heard when he makes them. The more outlandish, the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A proposed travel ban on Muslims galvanized his base, but when it was continually pointed out that it was in direct violation of the Constitution, Trump quietly reneged, saying it was “just a suggestion”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he has failed to provide clear solutions for the many logistical obstacles to building the wall. But to Trump, this is immaterial. He has never once let facts get in the way of his narrative, and he’s not about to start any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arguing the humanity of those who would be affected by this wall and the anti-immigrant language that accompanies it in the official party platform (it calls Barack Obama’s executive orders on immigration in 2012 and 2014 “unlawful amnesties” that must be rescinded) to Trump and his ardent supporters is a waste of breath. We in the Latino community know exactly where they stand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now, with the ratification of this platform, we know that the Republican party stands with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The platform is meant to reflect the soul of the party. In Cleveland, it became clear that this is now officially the party of Trump. If there ever was a Republican party that stood against xenophobia and racism, then that party has fallen, and it’s not just the newly empowered fringe that’s to blame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, many Republicans has tried to convince skeptics that the stereotypes weren’t true. The GOP wasn’t the party of bigotry. It wasn’t the party of racism or sexism or homophobia. These were lies from the left, meant to divide people and scare them away from conservative values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when a demagogue who was open in his contempt for immigrants and flagrant in his disdain for women came along with promises of a huge, impossible wall, the GOP caved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be ashamed of itself. What once claimed to be the party of Lincoln has surrendered its soul to a blowhard from reality TV, to a man they don’t even trust with access to a Twitter account, much less to nuclear launch codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To say that the party has been hijacked would be too gentle an assessment. Establishment Republicans are complicit in sewing the seeds of bigotry that would later bloom into Trumpism. They have helped to cultivate a culture of paranoia, a coalition of followers who are impervious to facts and act out of fear and anger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the kind of people you can sell a 2,000-mile wall to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As is the case with Trump himself, there is precious little substance here. The party platform does not go into specifics. It does not submit a timeline for construction or a budget for the mammoth costs it will incur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It exists instead as a cultural affirmation, as an assertion of identity: we are the party that builds walls.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/backing-for-the-wall-spells-the-end-of-republican-decency/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/backing-for-the-wall-spells-the-end-of-republican-decency/</guid>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        <category>opinion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Republican platform is extremist – and so is anyone who supports it</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It endorses ‘conversion therapy’. It rejects marriage equality. Incredibly, it’s to the right of Donald Trump. This is a party that has abandoned the mainstream&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“While activists like to claim that pedophilia is a completely distinct orientation from homosexuality, evidence shows a disproportionate overlap between the two,” Tony Perkins wrote on the Family Research Council website &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/individual/tony-perkins&quot;&gt;in 2010&lt;/a&gt;. “It is a homosexual problem.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such views are perhaps to be expected from the president of the FRC, a fiercely anti-LGBTQ organization that, using faith as a justification, has propagated the insidious view that gay people are sexual predators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mainstream Republicans might deem Perkins a fringe character. At the very least, they would probably want to distance themselves from a man who once purchased &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rightwingwatch.org/content/picture-worth-thousand-memories&quot;&gt;Klansman David Duke’s email list&lt;/a&gt; for use in a political campaign in Louisiana (Perkins now claims he wasn’t aware of the mailing list’s connection to Duke).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, it’s Perkins and his ilk who have emerged as the GOP’s moral compass in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.advocate.com/election/2016/7/11/republican-platform-takes-stands-against-restroom-access-ex-gay-therapy&quot;&gt;crafting the party platform&lt;/a&gt; ahead of the national convention in Cleveland. Perkins, an RNC delegate from Louisiana, succeeded in his push to add language to the platform supporting “conversion therapy”, a practice banned in several states that “re-educates” children to become cisgender and heterosexual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the platform, which was approved in committee on Tuesday, supports state laws that bar transgender people from public bathrooms and includes language that says “natural marriage”, marriage between a man and a woman, is more likely to produce offspring who do not become addicted to drugs. It also declares pornography a “public health crisis”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Republican moderates failed in their bid to include language acknowledging anti-gay discrimination in the wake of the Pulse massacre in Orlando, and so the platform heads to a formal vote next week bereft of any positive language on LGBTQ people whatsoever. It is unclear if the party will ratify it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is clear, however, is the influence of anti-LGBTQ fanatics and radical social conservatives in drawing up the platform, one that, incredibly, veers right of the party’s presidential nominee, Donald Trump, who desperately needs the support of the religious conservatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perkins is far from the only anti-LGBTQ activist who had a hand in creating the platform. The committee also includes David Barton from Texas, who has claimed that HIV/Aids is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rightwingwatch.org/content/barton-suggest-we-cant-cure-aids-because-it-punishment-sin&quot;&gt;God’s punishment for homosexuality&lt;/a&gt;, and Cynthia Dunbar from Virginia, who &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rightwingwatch.org/content/ted-cruzs-virginia-co-chair-tied-evolution-and-gay-rights-holocaust&quot;&gt;compares gay rights to Nazism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a dream team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The support for conversion therapy is especially heinous, considering it’s LGBTQ children who are typically the people who undergo it. Children cannot consent to this dangerous practice, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hrc.org/resources/the-lies-and-dangers-of-reparative-therapy&quot;&gt;statistics&lt;/a&gt; tell us that those who endure it are more likely to suffer from depression and are eight times more likely to have attempted suicide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same-sex marriage, of course, became the law of the land last year after the supreme court handed down its ruling on Obergefell v Hodges. But it’s an issue social conservatives are unwilling to let go of. Donald Trump himself claimed that he would “strongly consider” appointing supreme court justices who would overturn marriage equality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put together, the platform is an expression of the desire for LGBTQ people to disappear. It’s so bad that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.miamiherald.com/news/local/community/gay-south-florida/article89235362.html&quot;&gt;Log Cabin Republicans&lt;/a&gt; came out and called it the Republican party’s “most anti-LGBT platform in the party’s 162-year history”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sits in stark contrast to the Democratic party’s platform, which, while criticised by some for not doing more (the section on LGBTQ rights is a scant, singular paragraph), does take a strong stance on equality and says the party will fight for comprehensive federal non-discrimination protections for LGBTQ Americans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the Republican party platform isn’t just retrograde. It’s dangerous. It is the byproduct of the chaos presided over by an inexperienced, weak nominee, and it represents a stunning defeat for Republican moderates in the battle for the soul of their party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, any moderate who gives even tacit approval to a party that has positioned itself so squarely in opposition to the freedoms of LGBTQ cannot be considered a moderate at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 18:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/the-republican-platform-is-extremist-and-so-is-anyone-who-supports-it/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.johnpaulbrammer.com//work/the-republican-platform-is-extremist-and-so-is-anyone-who-supports-it/</guid>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        <category>opinion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
